MICHEAL POLLARD

Junior Business Analyst - Providing Data Management and Analysis for Strategic Decision-Making

+1-503-628-8758

♀ Dallas, TX

@ elonmusk@fakemail.com

@ linkedin.com/in/michaelpollard5

SUMMARY

Junior Business Analyst with 3+ of years of experience in customer-focused, dynamic environment. Highly apt at seeing beyond the numbers to provide systematic solutions to increase profit margins by an AVG of 20K/ year. Ability to listen with intent to the customer problems to gather data and find solutions to individual problems. Built a 5000+ customer database through the years, based on loyalty and respect.

EXPERIENCE

Junior Business Analyst

Carroll

2020 - Ongoing

Dallas, TX

Carroll is the global leader in cloud-based sales, marketing, learning, and customer experience solutions

- Increased gross revenue of 15% in 2021 (compared to 2020) with no change to fixed costs with data-oriented, customer-centric solutions
- Automated manual review process using excel that saved around 1- hour of work per
- Expanded BI Audience by an additional 200+ users by offering new insights and features

Research Associate & Intern Business Analyst

Grimes

2019 - 2020

Dallas, TX

Grimes is the alternative within top-tier executive search and part of the global top-10 executive search firm TRANSEARCH International - one of the leading executive search and leadership advisory organizations in the world.

- Improved internal processes by creating manuals to cut back on training time by 30%
- Reduced IPS (Customer Issues) by 2.2% while impacting merely 3% of GMV
- Supported sales to achieve 132% and 162% quota in 2019 and 2020

Sales Associate

Borer Ltd

2018 - 2019

Bronx. NY

Borer Ltd is an affiliate brand mainly focused on audience based programmatic display marketing

- Exceeded the incremental spend target by 120% due to providing personalized and customer-focused information
- Turned 2500+ cold leads into customers by offering them solutions to their problems and listening carefully to their concerns
- Helped with 150+ product launches by making cold calls, collecting and analyzing customer data

TRAINING / COURSES

Microsoft Excel Expert (Excel and Excel 2019)

Data Analysis for Decision-Making

Microsoft

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate

Coursera

SKILLS

Data Analysis

Client Management

Sales Targets

Cold Calling

Lead Generation

MS₀

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Business and **Political Economy**

New York University

STRENGTHS



Data Management

Systematic approach towards systematizing and analyzing data with Macros in Excel. Providing growth-focused solutions, increasing profit margins by at least 25%/ year.



Customer Growth by 15K/ Year

Knowledge of specific niches to implement business growth solutions: from product launches to lead generation. Accumulating a loyal customer base, responsible for the 30% expansion of the business within the past year.



Product Expansion

Using systematized data to provide opportunities with a focus on enhancing the overall customer experience by an annual AVG of 65%.

ACHIEVEMENTS



Successful launch of 100+ new products

Solely through the past 2 years, have provided datafocused solutions to increase sales on new unites by



High Achiever Q4 2021

Received the company-wide recognition for helping the sales team surpass their targets by 150%.